<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: deltaepsilon | Not a blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/categories/deltaepsilon/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.notadomain.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-11T17:02:06+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.notadomain.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Moritz Grauel]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Opportunities of scale]]></title>
<link href="http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/2012/11/15/opportunities-of-scale/"/>
<updated>2012-11-15T12:34:00+08:00</updated>
<id>http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/2012/11/15/opportunities-of-scale</id>

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We tend to forget how huge China is. Yeah, China is big and there are many Chinese. But how <em>many</em> Chinese there are, just needs a reminder from time to time.</p>

<p>According to <a href="http://www.wolframalpha.com/input/?i=population+china+vs+eu">Wolfram Alpha</a>, the population of china was estimated to be 1.3 billion in 2010. That is easily more, than the population of the EU and the USA combined.</p>

<p>This has a some peculiar consequences. For once, there are quite a few multi-million citizen cities, you've likely never heard of before. Would you know, where to search for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zhoukou">Zhoukou</a> or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linyi">Linyi</a> on the map? They both have a population of around 10 Million - give or take.</p>

<p>Another interesting consequence, there are a lots of hugely popular services and companies, that you have also probably never heard of - some of them more interesting than others.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://twitter.com">Twitter</a> equivalent of China for example is <a href="http://weibo.com">Sina Weibo</a>. While being mostly unknown in the western world, Weibo is about the same size as Twitter. According to the wikipedia, Twitter has currently about 500 million users and generates about 340 million messages a day. The 3 year old Weibo currently has about 368 million users and generates 100 million messages a day - not as much but the same order of magnitude (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">source</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sina_Weibo">source</a>).</p>

<p>Just as Weibo is quite similar to Twitter, there are many other china-only competitors to the services, we know. Yesterday, we used a very neat one. The site is called <a href="http://www.360buy.com/">360buy.com</a> (Strangely, many of the Chinese alternatives use .com instead of .cn TLDs). From the looks of it, they appear to be a competitor to <a href="http://www.amazon.de/?_encoding=UTF8&amp;camp=1638&amp;creative=19454&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;site-redirect=de&amp;tag=notadomaincom-21">amazon</a>. Yet, 360buy has a cool feature: In many areas, including Beijing, they offer <em>same-day-delivery</em>. For free. Just like that.</p>

<p>We decided, we needed to get a cheep DVD player for the TV in our apartment. We went to 360buy, used Chrome to translate the page, chose a device, entered our address and clicked on order. This was around 9:00 am. The same day at around 5:00 pm, it knocked on the door. We payed in cash and got our DVD player.</p>

<p>The whole experience was fast, friendly and due to Chromes page translate-feature, even possible for lazy aliens, that don't speak Chinese.</p>

<p>Part of me wants that from amazon <em>(in Germany)</em>!</p>

<p><a rel="bookmark" href="http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/2012/11/15/opportunities-of-scale/">&infin; Permalink</a></p>

]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Small Differences: Money]]></title>
<link href="http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/2012/11/10/small-differences-money/"/>
<updated>2012-11-10T12:24:00+08:00</updated>
<id>http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/2012/11/10/small-differences-money</id>

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Of course china uses money like everywhere else. And a lot of payments are done using cash. But the cash here is a bit different than in Europe.</p>

<p>This mainly boils down to the fact, that the biggest bill available in china is the 100 RMB bill. This is currently worth roughly 12.50 €. All other bills are worth even less. Also, coins are used far less often and only go up to 1 RMB (about 0.12 €).</p>

<p>This has two interesting consequences. First: You always have a trousers pocket full of papermoney. A thick stack of bills which is worth about 10 €. I kind of like that. Far more comfy than having a pocket full of €-coins. And still worth so little, that you don't really care if you lose a bill. (I guess this is similar in the US with their 1 $ bill).</p>

<p>The second consequence is, whenever you have to pay for something a bit more expensive, you deal with huge stacks of money. Making you feel a bit like a gangster in the first moment and making you wish, you had a counting machine the moment after that. (Counting machines are extremely common in china. Basically every cash register has one).</p>

<p>Did I mention, we payed our entire 3 month rent and a safety deposit in cash? This is how some of it looked:</p>

<p><img src="http://com.notadomain.blogbucket.s3.amazonaws.com/images/Cash.jpg" title="Lots of cash" ></p>

<p>Really, you have to deal with silly big stacks of cash from time to time. You have to make multiple trips to an ATM to get reasonable amounts of cash because they can't spit out stacks big enough. Stuff like that.</p>

<p>Apparently there is also quite a lot of counterfeit money in the wild. The Chinese will always check 50 and 100 RMB bills for validity. Either by hand or by feeding it through a counting machine.</p>

<p>And there is also the other side of the value spectrum. The smallest bill in circulation (and not quite uncommon) is the 1 Yi Jiao bill, aka 0.1 RMB. So it is roughly worth 1 euro cent.</p>

<p>On the street, prices are usually multiples of 1 RMB. Amounts below 1 RMB are usually only found in supermarkets and similar stores. So you usually put your Yi Jiaos somewhere and hope to remember theme the next time you are grocery shopping.</p>

<p>This is how it looks:</p>

<p><img src="http://com.notadomain.blogbucket.s3.amazonaws.com/images/worthless.jpg" title="Worthless money" ></p>

<p>It has roughly the same size and feel as monopoly money. Only, it is worth slightly less then monopoly money.   <p><a rel="bookmark" href="http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/2012/11/10/small-differences-money/">&infin; Permalink</a></p></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Small differences: Prepaid]]></title>
<link href="http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/2012/10/29/small-differences/"/>
<updated>2012-10-29T18:37:00+08:00</updated>
<id>http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/2012/10/29/small-differences</id>

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Preface</h1>

<p>We've been in Beijing for over a month by now. After that time I feel quite confident in saying, that Beijing is just another big city. It is quite <em>western</em> and very big. If you look at it from a high enough level, it is very similar to other big cities. There is public transportation. People have jobs. There is a large middle class. People buy designer clothes in huge malls. Just the usual.</p>

<p>It is the same shit like home, albeit <em>some</em> things are different. If you zoom in close enough, you can see lots of small differences. In the way, the city works, the society works. Really, it's all over the place. In the <em>Small Differences</em> series of posts, I plan to point out those differences, I found noticeable.</p>

<h1>Small Differences: Prepaid</h1>

<p>Having a prepaid cell phone is a very common thing here in Beijing like in many other big cities all around the globe. However, cell phones are not the only thing coming as prepaid variant over here. A few days ago, we had to find out, that also gas, water and electricity are often prepaid in China. And how do you discover something like that? Of course by standing under the shower and enjoying a lack of warm water. We complained to the landlord and low and behold - the next day someone came with a smart card, shoved it somewhere into the gas-meter and everything was fine again.</p>

<p>They also showed us the cards. This is a bit useless since we have no idea at all how to recharge those cards. But I can at least show them here. In order from top to bottom: Water, electricity and gas.</p>

<p><img src="http://com.notadomain.blogbucket.s3.amazonaws.com/images/Prepaid.jpg"></p>

<p>If you think about it, it actually isn't that bad of an idea. At least people can't get in situations, where they all of a sudden have to repay huge sums because they used more gas then anticipated.</p>

<p>I will write about heating here another time. There is a small difference to heating as well, although it is not prepaid like gas, water and electricity.</p>

<p><a rel="bookmark" href="http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/2012/10/29/small-differences/">&infin; Permalink</a></p>

]]></content>
    </entry>
  
</feed>

