<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: china | Not a blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/categories/china/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.notadomain.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-11T17:06:40+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.notadomain.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Moritz Grauel]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Take a deep breath]]></title>
<link href="http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/2012/10/11/take-a-deep-breath/"/>
<updated>2012-10-11T16:49:00+08:00</updated>
<id>http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/2012/10/11/take-a-deep-breath</id>

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks before we started our journey, a friend of mine gave me a
link to an article in the german Tagesspiegel (<a href="http://www.tagesspiegel.de/weltspiegel/leben-in-china-dicke-luft-in-peking-/6848760.html">link</a>). The author of that article stayed a while in Beijing as well. And according to her, the quality of the air in Beijing is usually so bad,
it took the author over a week to realize that her apartment had a view
on the mountains.</p>

<p>When we arrived in Beijing, we had a clear blue sky. So naturally, I was
thinking the author exaggerated a bit. That is, until yesterday, when I
realized that our apartment had a view on the mountains as well. It took
us <em>just</em> five days to realize that.</p>

<p>I took a picture from our window that morning. Today – also a nice
day with lots of sun – I tried to take the same picutre again. Same ISO, same
aperture, same shutter speed, roughly the same time of the day. I merged those images. This is the result:</p>

<p>{% img https://www.dropbox.com/s/e211rvp9v1fnn6s/Airquality.jpg?dl=1 Overlay of a clear and a usual day %}</p>

<p>To be honest, I made one mistake. I let the camera on
auto-white-balance. This probably overstates the difference a bit.
Anyways, take a deep breath and enjoy.</p>

<p><a rel="bookmark" href="http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/2012/10/11/take-a-deep-breath/">&infin; Permalink</a></p>

]]></content>
    </entry>
  
</feed>

