<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: misc | Not a blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/categories/misc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.notadomain.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-01T16:00:31+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.notadomain.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Moritz Grauel]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Berlin → Москва → Иркутск → 北京 → ???]]></title>
<link href="http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/2012/09/11/big-travel/"/>
<updated>2012-09-11T21:20:00+08:00</updated>
<id>http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/2012/09/11/big-travel</id>

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_madug76njY1rgtzh1o1_1280.jpg" title="'Ready to go on a tour'" ></p>

<p>On thrusday, in just a few short days, we will start quite a big travel.
First stop will be Moscow, where we stay for a day before we head on to
lake baikal for a week of hiking and vacation.</p>

<p>Next stop will be china. <em>A.</em> will be doing an internship in Beijing
starting in October and I will give her company as long as I'm permitted
to stay in China. Sadly it is not possible to stay in China as a tourist
for as long as an intern.</p>

<p>When my permission to stay in China expires, we will have to part our
ways for a few weeks. I will move on to South Korea and Japan (and maybe
some more places where I don't need a complicated visa).</p>

<p>At the end of december, we will rejoin at beijing airport to fly back
home together. Or at least that is the plan.</p>

<p>All of this is surely going to be very exciting and we are looking
forward to it a lot (although from time to time a bit nervously). Did I
mention, we don't really speak any chinese language?</p>

<p>As a result of our travels, over the next few weeks and months, the focus of
this blog might shift a bit away from technical topics over to
documenting our travels.</p>

<p>Since I'm not sure about the conditions of the intertube access along
the way, this might be more or less complicated. I might have trouble
posting to this blog, therefore I've also set up accounts over at
<a href="http://mo-gr.tumblr.com">tumblr</a> and <a href="http://mo-gr.posterous.com">posterous</a>.
And be sure to also follow me on <a href="http://twitter.com/mo_gr">twitter</a> if
you want to stay up to date.</p>

<p>We will post pictures and status updates to at least one of those places
in a semi regular fashion.</p>

<p><a rel="bookmark" href="http://blog.notadomain.com/blog/2012/09/11/big-travel/">&infin; Permalink</a></p>

]]></content>
    </entry>
  
</feed>

